

CONTACT

Phone:

+49 175 / 649 50 50

Mail:

verenatraubmail@qmail.com

Web:

verenatraub.netlify.app







SKILLS

Hands-on experience in:

- HTML & CSS
- SASS & Handlebars
- JavaScript (ES6)
- React
- ExpressJS
- NodeJS
- Leaflet
- MongoDB & Mongoose
- Axios
- Github, Gitlab, Jira

On my current learning & project list:

- TypeScript
- NextJS
- Cypress

Toolbox:

Scrum & Kanban

Languages:

German - Mother tongue English - fluent Polish - basic skills

Jagstzell, December 2021

VERENA TRAUB

Rookie-Developer with an agile skillset who discovered her passion for programming - and now after several years in tech recruiting would love to turn this into a carreer.

What I bring to the table? A solid foundation thanks to a successfully completed coding bootcamp, a large portion of passion and willingness to learn as well as the ability to quickly and independently familiarize myself with new topics.

WORK EXPERIENCE

06/2021 - 11/2021

Junior Frontend Developer (Freelance) - aiconix GmbH, Hamburg

- Supporting the development team on their real-time transcription sytem
- Project: Refactoring and further improvements on the "Emergency Button" feature to turn subtitles off and on during live streaming
- TechStack: NextJS, DraftJS, Typescript

Since 03/2017

Founder, CEO & Lead Recruiter - yngage GmbH, Hamburg & Baden-Württemberg

- Interim Management as Tech Recruiter and Scrum Master for clients such as it agile, ThoughtWorks Spain, Equal Experts, aiconix or For Sale Digital
- Workshops and trainings about recruiting, Employer Branding or agile HR / agile recruiting

12/2013 - 02/2017

Freelane Consultant & Interim Manager, Hamburg

- Interim Management as Tech Recruiter and Scrum Master for clients such as SinnerSchrader, XING, ThoughtWorks Deutschland or Brandslisten
- Workshops and trainings about recruiting, Employer Branding or agile HR / agile recruiting

01/2011 - 11/2013

Recruiting Manager - CoreMedia AG, Hamburg

- Tech-Recruiting
- Employer Branding and HR marketing
- Contact person for managers and employees

12/2008- 12/2010

Omikron Data Quality GmbH, Pforzheim

- 11/2009 12/2010: HR Manager with focus on further developing the HR function as well as tech recruiting
- 12/2008 10/2009: Assistant of the CEO and HR Management

EDUCATION

10/2020 - 04/2021

Full-Stack Web-Development Bootcamp - Ironhack (remote)

- Frontend technologies: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React
- Backend technologies: ExpressJS, NodeJS, MongoDB, Mongoose, Axios
- Design and development of 3 different projects (see below)

10/2015

Certified Scrum Master (CSM)

training by it-agile (Hamburg), certification by Scrum Alliance (remote)

02/2007 - 08/2008

Studies in Business Administration - Akademia Ekonomiczna w Poznaniu, Poznan (Polen)

- Final degree: German diploma and Polish magister in Business Administration
- Final grade: 1,6
- Focus disciplines: Business Informatics, Marketing, International Business, Business English

10/2004 - 02/2007

Studies in Business Administration - TU Bergakademie Freiberg, Freiberg

PROJECTS

EyeBird - an app for bird lovers

Tech Stack: JavaScript, React, ExpressJS, NodeJS, MongoDB, Mongoose,

Leaflet, Axios, SASS, React-Bootstrap, HTML & CSS

Github: https://github.com/vtrHH/nature-app

Demo: https://eyebird.netlify.app/

Mooseician - a marketplace for musicians

Tech Stack: JavaScript, ExpressJS, NodeJS, Handlebars, MongoDB, Mongoose,

SASS, Bootstrap, HTML & CSS

Github: https://github.com/vtrHH/musicians-app
Demo: https://mooseician.herokuapp.com/

Mask Game - an online game

Tech Stack: HTML & CSS, HTML Canvas, JavaScript

Github: https://qithub.com/vtrHH/ironhack-project1-mask-game

Demo: https://verena-mask-game.netlify.app/

More projects at <u>verenatraub.netlify.app</u>

ABOUT ME

Since 07/2017

Mother of a wonderful son

Since 02/2016

Organizer of the Agile meets HR Meetup, Hambura

(since 2020 with additional groups in Berlin and Munich)

Since 03/2011

Lecturer, Career Center of the University of Hamburg, Hamburg as well as remote